Guide to the Alexander M. Drummond papers, 1917-1956.
Drummond, Alexander M. papers, 1917-1956
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alexander M. Drummond papers, 1917-1956.
14-24-435
A. M. (Alexander Magnus) Drummond, 1884-1956.
19.2 cubic feet
Correspondence, news clippings, scripts, programs, playbills, lecture notes, theater notes, photographs, recordings and other memorabilia.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, news clippings, scripts, programs, playbills, lecture notes, theater notes, photographs, recordings and other memorabilia relating to various aspects of the field of Speech and Drama.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Speech and Drama, Cornell University.
Organized the Cornell Dramatic Club and was its Director from 1912-1947. Wrote original plays and a monograph on play production.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, news clippings, scripts, programs, playbills, lecture notes, theater notes, photographs, recordings and other memorabilia relating to various aspects of the field of Speech and Drama.
Includes charcoal drawing of Professor Drummond by Christian Midjo.
Includes correspondence from Eugene O'Neill, Oscar Hammerstein II, George Bernard Shaw and Hendrik Van Loon.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Drummond, A. M. (Alexander Magnus), 1884-1956.; Hammerstein, Oscar, 1895-1960.; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953.; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950.; Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1882-1944.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Speech and Drama Dept.; Cornell University. Cornell Dramatic Club.
Subjects:
Drama--Study and teaching.; College theater--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Theater reviews.; Theatrical publishing.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scripts (documents); Playbills.; Theater programs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Selected correspondence available on microfilm.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Plays and Writings
Series IV. Teaching and Professorship
Series V. Photographs and Glass Slides
Series VI. Clippings
Series VII. Scripts
Series VIII. Programs
Series IX. Oversized Items
Series X. Audio
Series XI. Miscellaneous
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection #14-24-1143.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical
  - Biographical Information, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Membership Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Passport and Greece Photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Address Books, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Autograph Book, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hamilton College Publications, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Drummond Family Information, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hamilton College, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, March 11, 1950 - March 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Drummond Speech at Hamilton College on reception of an honorary degree, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Items Pertaining to Drummond's Estate, February 21, 1955 - May 21, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Estate Correspondence, 1950 - 1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Typescript of Radio Speeches by Sam Horton about Drummond, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "The Professor and the Critic", May 12, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence about the Drummond portrait painted by Midjo, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "The Taxpayer Looks at Our Public Schools." by R. W. Drummond, April 15, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Will of Anna E. Drummond, February 21, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lazy "C" Ranch Warranty Deed, January 15, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Council of Senior Citizens of Tompkins County Newsletters, August - October 1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - YMCA War Work Brochure, April 1, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1906-1916 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1917 - May, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, June - December, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, January - March, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, April - December, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, January - October, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, November, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, December 1, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, January - September, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, October - December, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, January - March, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, April - October, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, March - May, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, June - July, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, August - December, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, January - May, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence, May - July, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, August - December, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, January - August, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, September - December, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, January - April, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, May - September, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, October - December, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, January - March, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, April - August, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, September - December, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January - March, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, April - December, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January - March, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, April - 1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, January - August, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, September - December, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January - April, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, May - August, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, September - October, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, March - April, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, May - July, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, August - October, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, March - April, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, May - June, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, July - October, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, March - April, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, May - June, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, July - August, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, August - October, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, April - May, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, June - August, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, September - October, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, January -February, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, March - April, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, May - June, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, July - August, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, September - October, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, March - May, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, May 14 - 21, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, May 22 - 31, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1 - 4, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Jun 5 - 12, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, June - August, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, September - October, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, March - April, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, May - June, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, July - August, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, September - October, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, March - May, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, June - October, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, November - December, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, January - May, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, June - August, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, September - December, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, January - May, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, June - September, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, October - December, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Barnard Hewitt
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Constance Kuhn
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Robert Gard
  - Correspondence, 1935 - 1936 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Stephen Raushenbush; "Bugles at Noon"
- Series III. Plays and Writings
  - Correspondence, 1938 - 1945 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Mostly with Robert Gard
  - Playwright's Notebook of New York State, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Theatre in America, 1750 - 1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - A Dramatist Looks at Public Speaking, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - How to Choose a Play and How to Write One, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Romantic New York State Bibliography, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Romantic New York State, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Indian "Treaties", February, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - A Countryside Theatre Experiment, February, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - A Manual of Play Production, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Plays for the Country Theatre, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Play Production for the Country Theatre, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - The Country Theatre, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Traffic Signals: A Modern Morality in Two Acts, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Traffic Signals: A Jazz Morality, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    typescript; complete copy
  - Traffic Signals: A Jazz Morality, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    typescript; incomplete copy
  - Traffic Signals, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Script used by CDC
  - Traffic Signals, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Script drafts and edits
  - Traffic Signals Programs, 1936, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    CDC; Iowa State College Theatre
  - Traffic Signals, 1936, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    publicity and reviews
  - Original cast lists for plays printed in Cornell University Plays, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Hope Chest, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Lake Guns of Seneca and Cayuga, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    published script
  - The Lake Guns of Seneca and Cayuga, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Act II - typescript
  - The Lake Guns of Seneca and Cayuga, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    typescript
  - The Lake Guns of Seneca and Cayuga, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    notes, reviews and book cover
  - The Lake Drums, August 26, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Material for Prof. Drummond left by H.W. Thompson
  - The Cardiff Giant, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    typescript; includes chapter from A.D. White's autobiography
  - The Cardiff Giant, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - The Cardiff Giant, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    typescript with edits
  - The Cardiff Giant, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    script excerpts for Barnum, Hull and Colonel Ingersoll
  - The Cardiff Giant, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - The Cardiff Giant, March 20, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    notes and research materials
  - The Cardiff Giant, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    drafts and notes
  - The Cardiff Giant, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    photographs, programs and publicity
  - The Cardiff Giant, June 15, 1939 - November, 11 1950 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    programs, reviews and publicity
  - Untitled Scripts, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Articles by Drummond, 1917 - 1923 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Proposal for Dramas from American Life and Theatre, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Headings for book chapters, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    book title not indicated
  - "Right Pronunciation of Names for Untravelled Readers from Travels Through the Western Country", undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Copyright and Agents, March 3, 1928 - April 21, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Introduction to Lake Guns of Seneca and Cayuga, and Eight Other Plays from Upstate New York, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Series IV. Teaching and Professorship
  - Outline of Topics for Lectures on American Drama & Theatre, 1936 - 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Term paper lists; play lists
  - Carbon Copy of Materials on the American Drama & Theatre, September, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Index to Folders: American Theatre & Drama, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Syllabus: American Drama & Theatre, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Theatre in Life, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    American characters; theatre documenting events
  - The Theatre in Life, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    funeral customs; social history of theatre
  - Settlement of America & The Beginnings, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    early theatre in US cities
  - Indian Plays and Actors, 1944 - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Heroines
  - Pre-revolutionary Period, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Washington & the theatre; British army theatre
  - Revolutionary Rhetorical Plays, 1945 - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    partisan plays; non-partisan plays
  - Post Revolutionary Theatre, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Early Theatres and Companies, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Early Pageantry & Spectacles, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Heroic Spectacle; American Circus; Term papers
  - American Theatre - 19th Century, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Audiences, Actors; Richmond; Amusement Guild
  - Music and the American Theatre, 1946 - 1948 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    The Hutchinsons; America Learns to Play
  - The Negro and the American Character, 1943 - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Minstrelsy
  - Panoramas, 1941 - 1948 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Diorama; Panorama; Solar microscope; History; Ediophoscion; Amsterdam; Peep show; Photographs; Letters (Divided into two folders)
  - Steele Mackaye, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Excerpt from The Little Locksmith
  - Vaudeville, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Joe Howard; Stars; Showmanship
  - Film, Radio, Stage, 1941 - 1947 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Colleges and film; Newspaper clippings
  - Colleges and Little Theatres, 1941 - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Play catalogues; Newspaper clippings
  - Community and Theatre, 1943 - 1948 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Description of Oneida NY theatre; Soap operas; Swanzey Players; Toby Players; War and politics
  - Censorship, 1926 - 1948 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    At Cornell; American, English, German and Russian censorship (Divided into two folders)
  - Heroines and Plays, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Ideal Heroine; Romantic Lady; Negro heroine
  - Humor and Character, 1837 - 1942 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Henry James; Native Humor; Manners; Morals; Rourke
  - Chief Costume Changes in America, 1607 - 1865, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Term paper and summary
  - Dance and the Theatre, 1939 - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Bali-Javanese dance; American ballet; Musical comedy
  - Early Theatres and Companies, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Farce; Humor; Coopers' gleanings
  - Drama and Theatre in Comparison, 1941 - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Index To Lecture Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Playwrights and Playwriting, 1944 - 1948 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Tennessee Williams; Henry James; Prose writers; Misc. articles
  - Contemporary Theatre, 1946 - 1947 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    General Information; Ad libbing; Audience attendance; Theatre business
  - The Theatre of the Future, 1929 - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Theatre after 1929; Abstract of The Awakening of American Theatre; Complete article "The Plight of the Theatre Business"
  - World War I and 20th Century, 1914 - 1947 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Movies; radio; automobiles and sports as competing with theatre; Make-up; Small hits; First nights
  - Theatre and War, 1863 - 1943 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    War plays/films; Propaganda dram; Pericles' Funeral Oration; Greek Drama; Lincoln and Civil War
  - Misc. Notes and Reports, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Lecture 1: Theatricalization in American Life, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Roots of American culture; Folk art; Personal letter describing the funeral of A.S. McPherson
  - Lecture 2: Settlement of America and Beginnings, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Early craze for dancing; Pilgrims and asceticism
  - Lecture 3: Indian Treaties; Ritual Drama, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Treaties; Early plays; Term papers
  - Lecture 4: Pre-Revolutionary Culture, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Paul Revere; Mechanical wonders; Theatre experiences before, during and after the Revolutionary War; George Washington
  - Lecture 5: Theatre before the Revolution, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    Restoration in England; English Drama pre-Colonies
  - Lecture 6: The British Army Theatre, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Lecture 7: Rhetorical Plays, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    Calvanism as dramatic faith; Sermon-dialogues; Partisan rhetorical plays; Student Drama; Two Dartmouth plays
  - Lecture 8: Theatres & Companies After the Revolution, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    Early theatres and theatregoing
  - Lecture 9: William Dunlap, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Lecture 10: Patriotic Comedies, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Lecture 11: Indian Plays & Actors", undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    Term paper; Origin and Characteristics
  - Lecture 12: The Negro in the Theatre, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    Five term papers; The Negro as a romantic heroine
  - Lecture 13: Early Spectacle, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    Heroic Spectacle; Drama; Ballet; Burlesques; Variety; Circus; Amphitheatre; Term paper
  - Lecture 14: The Frontier Theatre, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    Early "western" shows in Europe; Term paper; Showboat; Buffalo Bill
  - Lecture 15: The Theatre of the Actor, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    Chronology of celebrated actors; Actors and styles; 19th Century theatre
  - Lecture 16: Music in the Theatre, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
    Nationalism; Musical romanticism; Minstrelsy; Indian melodies; Music and spiritual emancipation
  - Lecture 17: Panoramas, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
    Odell references in NY Stage to panorama exhibitions; Diorama; Painting; Scenery
  - Lecture 18: Anti-Slavery Propaganda, 1942 - 1945 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    Uncle Tom's Cabin and modern banning; Lincoln assassination; Plays with slavery/Civil War themes
  - Lecture 19: Steele Mackaye, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Term paper; Playwriting; Inventions; Biography
  - Lecture 20: Belascan Realism, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    Term paper; Works and contributions of Belasco
  - Lecture 21: the Theatrical Syndicate, undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
    Controlling business procedures; The Shuberts
  - Lecture 22: The Rise of Realism, 1944 - 1945 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    Realist tradition in American art and drama; Revolt against romanticism
  - Lecture 23: The Rise of American Plays; International Copyright Frees American Playwrights, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    Term paper
  - Lecture 24: Percy Mackaye, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lecture 25: American Vaudeville, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Early days
  - Lecture 26: The New "Stagecraft" in America, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Lecture 27: The Rise of the Movies, 1944 - 1947 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Movies vs. the stage; Movie-making in Ithaca
  - Lecture 28: The Provincetown Theatre, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Little theatres
  - Lecture 29: Experimental Theatre: Theatre Guilds & Group Theatre, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Two term papers
  - Lecture 30: College and University Theatre, 1942 - 1943 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    The Coburn controversy; University sponsored theatre
  - Lecture 31: Regional Theatre, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Lecture 32: National Theatre: Federal Theatre and ATNA, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Living newspaper; Term paper
  - Lecture 33: Censorship, 1941 - 1948 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Two term papers; History and points of view on censorship
  - Lecture 34: Ithaca Theatres and Early Entertainments, Central NY, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Misc. newspaper clippings; articles and references
  - Lecture 35: An American Repertory, 1941 - 1942 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Remarks, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Graduate Students, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - American University of Ellis Hollow, NY, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Unacceptable Plays, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Heerman's Lectures and Prizes, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    American themed one-act competition
  - Newsletters - Cornell Department of Public Speaking and Dramatics, 1936 - 1950 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Cornell University Theatre Financial Statements, 1941 - 1951 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Cornell Summer School Statistics, 1933 - 1944 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Graduate Student Statistics, 1941 - 1944 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Winans Studies in Rhetoric and Oratory, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Personal letters and finances
  - Phonetics and Elocution, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Lee S. Hultzen
  - Cornell Speech & Drama, 1942 - 1949 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Syllabus and Exam
  - Playwriting Contests and Library Reserves, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Book orders and new acquisitions for Cornell libraries, 1947 - 1948 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Scenery trailer design by J.C. Lewis, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Cornell Dramatic Club finances, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - History of the Department and the CDC, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Theatre Department and Cornell Dramatic Club Documents, 1930 - 1952 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    Playbills; Newspaper articles; Personal letters
  - Cornell Dramatic Club finances, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Dramatic Art, 1931 (?) (Box 6, Folder 32)
    At Cornell; Development and Support
  - Cornell Dramatic Club Workers, 1943 - 1944 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - CDC Constitution in the Forties, 1946 - 1948 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - CDC Business, 1939 - 1951 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    Statistics; Members; Finances; Productions; Policy
  - CDC Constitutions, 1910 - 1936 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    Constitutions; Amendments; Incorporation; Women's Club
  - CDC Gift Fund, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - CDC Clippings, 1942 - 1947 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    Newspaper articles; One-acts; Summer School; Contests
  - CDC and Cornell Summer Players, 1917 - 1954 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    Newspaper clippings; Playbills; Daily Sun articles